NUNO LOUREIRO

Musician, computer programmer and media artist nunovloureiro@gmail.com | nunoloureiro.info

2016: Mada Treku - Festival Liberdade Gourmet

SELECTED PROJECTS:

<u>Lorr No</u>: main solo electronic music adventures. Sound based composition. Weird self-built samplers live performances.

Fugly: guitar grinding garage rock band with my friends.

<u>Solar Corona</u>, dubbbbbbbb fx fast paced pocaterra pocaterra heavy music.

<u>Mada Treku</u>: old (and bad) solo moniker for previous main solo electronic music adventures.

OGBE: guitar and bass and drums improv weirdo hand gestures orchestra.

<u>Everything is beautiful and nothing hurts</u>: online radio for people who enjoy listening to local albums that I think are cool.

<u>Favela Discos</u>: art/music/intelectual/freak/good people collective operating in Porto since 2013.

Ramal: the most resilient art/music platform ever for 15 people at a time.

SELECTED PERFORMANCES:

```
2020: Lorr No - Maus Hábitos
2020: Desilusão Óptica - Passos Manuel
2020: Milteto - Café au Lait
2020: Solar Corona - Maus Hábitos
2019: Lorr No - Ramal 01
2019: Lorr No - Pérola Negra
2019: 2013: O Regresso - Understage Rivoli
2019: Fugly - Festival Super Bock Super Rock
2019: Fugly - Micro European Tour: Vigo, Capbreton, Tulle, Limoges
2018: Mada Treku - SILOS
2018: Fugly - Galeria Zé dos Bois
2018: Fugly - Festival Barreiro Rocks
2018: Fugly - Festa do Avante
2018: Fugly - Festival Paredes de Coura
2018: Fugly - Festival MIL
2018: Fugly - European Tour: Spain, France, Belgium, Netherlands, Germany,
Poland, Italy
2017: Desilusão Óptica - Museu de qSerralves
2017: Mada Treku - supporting Moor Mother, Café au Lait
2017: Mada Treku - Micro Tour with Jung An Tagen, Sarnadas and Vasco da Ganza:
Lisbon, Caldas da Rainha, Vila Real, Porto
2017: Mada Treku - Passos Manuel
2016: Mada Treku - Casa da Musica
2016: Mada Treku - Festival Milhões de Festa
```

MULTIMEDIA WORK:

2021: Everything is beautiful and nothing hurts @ eibanh.pt

Website

reactive visuals with Hydra. div transmission using Icecast.

2021: Personal website @ nunoloureiro.info

Website

reactive animation with p5js. html, css and js.

2020: Kapua Waiata @ Festival MI | Albergaria-a-Velha, Portugal

<u>Installation</u> with José Alberto Gomes

reactive visuals with Processing. reactive audio with Max MSP.

2020: How to live well and truthfully in a city of unfinished dreams @ Mera's

Domestic Rave

Video with André Coelho

WORKSHOPS:

2020: Sound synthesis and non-linear music composition @ Festival Vaga / FBAUP, Porto, Portugal.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

2016-present: Professional musician

2016-2017: Producer (w/ João Sarnadas) @ Festival Liberdade Gourmet

2015-present: Freelance audio/music producer

2010-present: Freelance videographer

Feb 2019-Feb 2020: Portuguese language instructor @ Berlitz Virtual Classroom

Apr 2015-Jun 2016: Receptionist @ Porto Spot Hostel

EDUCATION:

2020: Found Sound: Authorship and Appropriation with Geng @ Abrons Arts Center

2020: Formação de Formadores de Serviços Educativos e Mediação Artística with

Artur Carvalho @ Braga Media Arts

2020: Environment and Synthesis with Mark Fell and CM Von Hausswolff @ CampFR

2020: Presence with Laurel Halo @ CampFR

2018: International Conference for Live Interfaces | Porto, Portugal.

2016-2018: Multimedia Master @ FEUP | Porto, Portugal.

Interactive music and sound design specialisation

2011: C1 Advanced (CAE) @ Cambridge ESOL | Porto, Portugal.

2010-2013: Sound and Image Degree @ Escola das Artes UCP | Porto, Portugal.

SKILLS:

Programming: Pure Data, Max MSP, Processing, P%JS, Hydra, HTML, CSS, JS.

Audio: Ableton Live, Reaper, Logic Pro.

Video: Da Vinci Resolve, Adobe Premiere, Apple Final Cut.

Design: InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop.

Languages: Portuguese, English, some Spanish.

Riding, fixing and looking at bicycles.